Guide to the Julian C. Smith papers, 1900-2015.
Smith, Julian C. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Julian C. Smith papers, 1900-2015.
16-7-2474
Smith, Julian C.(Julian Cleveland),
23.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, professional records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Academic and professional papers, including correspondence, material on technical societies, records of his consulting work, and collected subject files. Includes information on his textbook Unit Operations of Chemical Engineering also indices of Ithaca Journal obituaries. Includes an extensive collection of daily diaries from throughout Smith's life and several scrapbooks. Other material includes family diplomas and correspondence related to his time spent working on the Manhattan Project.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Emeritus of Chemical Engineering, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Academic and professional papers, including correspondence, material on technical societies, records of his consulting work, and collected subject files. Includes information on his textbook Unit Operations of Chemical Engineering also indices of Ithaca Journal obituaries. Includes an extensive collection of daily diaries from throughout Smith's life and several scrapbooks. Other material includes family diplomas and correspondence related to his time spent working on the Manhattan Project.
Also, The School of Chemical Engineering at Cornell: A History of the First Fifty Years; Breaking Ninety, A History of the Country Club of Ithaca, 1900-1990; and "Family History: Julian C. Smith."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Smith, Julian C. 1919-2015; Smith family; Smith family.; Cornell University. College of Engineering -- History.; Cornell University. School of Chemical Engineering.; Cornell University. College of Engineering; Cornell University. School of Chemical Engineering; Country Club of Ithaca (Ithaca, N.Y.); Country Club of Ithaca (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Country clubs -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Chemical engineering -- study and teaching.; Chemical engineering -- Study and teaching; Country clubs
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Diaries in the collection from 1947 through Smith's death are restricted until 2046. Access to the diaries before then may be granted by permission of the family.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Boxes 8, 19-21
a. Personal Records
b. Financial Ledgers
c. Scrapbooks
d. Schooling Materials
e. Recognitions
1. Diplomas & Certificates
2. Plaques & Awards
f. Family Records
g. Photographs
h. Other
i. Museum Items
j. Reference Books
1. Memorial Statements & Related Materials
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 1, 5-6, 14, 17, 19
a. Personal Correspondence
b. Professional Correspondence
Series III. Publications & Related Materials
Boxes 10, 14, 18
a. Engineering Related
b. Other
c. Reviews
Series IV. Teaching & Cornell University
Boxes 2-4, 9-11, 13
a. Departmental
b. Graduate Program
c. Co-op Program
d. Heat Transfer Course
e. Equipment Courses
1. ChE 563: Process Equipment Design & Selection
2. ChE 5625
3. ChE 5609
f. Other Courses
1. Unknown
2. ChE 421: Organic Chemical Course
3. ChE 432: Unit Operations Lab Course
4. ChE 463: Synthetic Fuels
5. ChE 5041: Non-Resident Lectures
6. ChE 565
7. ChE 462: Design Course
8. ChE 461
g. Specialty Topics/Research
h. Lectures Outside Cornell
Series V. Patent
Box 11
Series VI. Consulting
Boxes 5-6, 12, 15, 17
Series VII. Organizations & Committees
Boxes 5, 7, 26
a. Organizations
b. Committees
Series VIII. Media
Box 1
Series IX. Separated Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - Personal Records
    - Personal Diaries, 1934 - 1973; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 19)
      Access restrictions apply.
    - Date Books, 1968 - 2004; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 8)
    - Personal Diaries & Travel Journals, 1974 - 1993; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 20)
    - Travel Journals, 1975-02-19 - 1990-06; Smith Jr., Julian C.; Smith, Joan E. (Box 20)
    - Personal Diaries, 1994 - 2015; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 21)
  - Financial Ledgers
    - Expenses, Etc., 1946-04-14 - 1948 (Box 8)
    - Home Related Finances Ledger, 1949 - 2001 (Box 8)
    - Income & Assets Ledger, 1951-01 - 1962-12 (Box 8)
    - Income & Expense Ledger, 1952-10-1 - 1983 (Box 8)
    - Income & Assets Ledger, 1963-01 - 1975-08 (Box 8)
    - Income & Assets Ledger, 1975-09 - 1987-12 (Box 8)
    - Consulting and other Professional Income & Expense Ledger, 1984-01-01 - 2004-10-27 (Box 8)
    - Computer Projects Ledger, 1986-01-01 - 2000-12-12 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Cornell Undergraduate Scrapbook, 1938 - 1942 (Box 8)
      Includes programs, photos, newspaper clippings, Alpha Delta Phi materials, telegrams, correspondence, The Cornell Engineer Vol. 5 No. 1, Cornell Daily Sun, golf score cards, Wendell Willkie for President buttons, Phi Kappa Phi materials, pencil sketches, rejection note from The New Yorker
      Cornell University; Ithaca, New York
    - Scrapbook, 1967-01-22 - 1976-05-23 (Box 8)
      Includes church service programs, newspaper clippings, photographs, cards, lyric sheets, concert programs
    - Julian C. Smith Dinner Scrapbook, 1983-10-21 (Box 22)
      Given "In honor of his term as Director, School of Chemical Engineering, Cornell University 1975-1983"
    - Scrapbook, 2002-04-23 - 2003-09-05 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, 2003-09-22 - 2004-03-26 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, 2004-03 - 2004-09 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, 2004-10 - 2005-05 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, 2005-07 - 2006-06-24 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, 2006-06-30 - 2007-07-18 (Box 22)
  - Schooling Materials
    - Westmount School Exercise Book, 1930 - 1936 (Box 1)
      Count: 3
      Westmount, Quebec
    - Westmount High School Annual, 1936-06; Westmount High School (Box 1)
      Includes photo of Editorial Board
    - Phillips Exeter Review, 1937; Phillips Exeter Academy (Box 1)
      Vol. IV No. 3
      Exeter, New Hampshire
    - Unit Operations Reports - Fluid Flow, 1940-10 - 1940-11-19 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Heat Transfer, 1940-11 - 1940-12-19 (Box 13)
      Report bound in 1983
    - Unit Operations Reports - Evaporation, 1940-12 - 1941-01-24 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Distillation, 1941-01 - 1941-03-11 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Gas Absorption, 1941-03 - 1941-04-21 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Filtration, 1941-03 - 1941-05-26 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Drying, 1941-04 - 1941-05-26 (Box 13)
    - Unit Operations Reports - Crushing and Grinding, 1941-05 - 1941-06-04 (Box 13)
    - Problem Solutions, 1941-10-01 - 1942-04-21 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Winding's Advanced Calculations Course
    - The Design of a Synthetic Petroleum Plant, 1942-05-06 (Box 13)
      Master's thesis
    - Phillips Exeter Academy Class of '37 45th Reunion, 1982-05-28 - 1982-05-30; Phillips Exeter Academy (Box 1)
  - Recognitions
    - Diplomas & Certificates
      - Westmount High School Leaving Certificate, 1936-07-31; Office of the Inspector of High Schools, Department of Education (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Phillips Exeter Academy Diploma, 1937-06-29; Phillips Exeter Academy (Box 25, Folder 2)
        English Department course of study
      - Phi Kappa Phi Membership Certificate, 1940-12-13 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Tau Beta Pi Membership Certificate, 1941-05-08 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Bachelor of Chemistry Diploma from Cornell University for Julian Cleveland Smith Jr., 1941-06-16; Cornell University (Box 25, Folder 2)
        Ithaca, New York
      - Sigma Xi Membership Certificate, 1942-03-25 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Master's of Chemical Engineering from Cornell University for Julian Cleveland Smith Jr., 1942-05-25; Cornell University (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - War Department Manhattan Project Certificate, 1945-08-06 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - U.S. Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Distinguished Civic Service Award, 1950; Ithaca Junior Chamber of Commerce (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - AIChE Certificate of Membership, 1954-06-17; American Institute of Chemical Engineers (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - License to Practice Professional Engineering, 1958-05-01; University of the State of New York (Box 25, Folder 3)
        New York
      - New York Academy of Sciences Certificate, 1959-11-19 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - AIChE Fellow Certificate, 1975-06-05; American Institute of Chemical Engineers (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Certificate of Appreciation, 1983; Chemical Engineering Advisory Council (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Registration Certificate to Practice Professional Engineering, 1988-10-31; University of the State of New York (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - John McMullen Scholarship Program, 1990-04-26 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - AIChE Half-Century of Membership, 1994; American Institute of Chemical Engineers (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Who's Who in the World Certificate, 2011; Marquis Who's Who Publications Board (Box 25, Folder 3)
        28th Edition
    - Plaques & Awards
      - Garfield-Perry Stamp Club Gold Award, 1982-03; MU-1726 (Box 24)
        Garfield-Perry Stamp Club
      - Scholarship Challenge Campaign Award, 1998-1999 (Box 24)
      - AIChE Warren K. Lewis Award, 2008; MU-1727 (Box 24)
        Awarded for contributions to Chemical Engineering Education
        American Institute of Chemical Engineers
  - Family Records
    - Degree of Mechanical Engineering Diploma from Cornell University for Julian Cleveland Smith Sr., 1900-06-21; Cornell University (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Father's diploma
      Smith Sr., Julian Cleveland; Ithaca, New York
    - Bachelor of Arts Diploma from Cornell University for Bertha Louise Alexander, 1901-06-20; Cornell University (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Mother's undergraduate diploma
      Alexander, Bertha Louise; Ithaca, New York
    - College Graduate Certificate of the State of New York for Bertha Louise Alexander, 1904-11-28; State Education Department (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Alexander, Bertha Louise; Albany, New York
    - Canadian Society of Civil Engineers Membership for Julian Cleveland Smith Sr., 1911-04-08; Canadian Society of Civil Engineers (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Smith Sr., Julian Cleveland; Montreal, Quebec
    - Fellow Diploma of American Institute of Electrical Engineers for Julian Cleveland Smith Sr., 1912-10-11; American Institute of Electrical Engineers (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Smith Sr., Julian Cleveland; New York
    - Juris Doctor from Queen's University for Julian Cleveland Smith Sr., 1923-05-07; Queen's University (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Father's "LL.D." diploma
      Smith Sr., Julian Cleveland; Kingston, Ontario
    - Women of Canada, 1930; Women of Canada Publishing Company (Box 1)
      Includes entry "Mrs. Julian C. Smith" (Bertha Louise Alexander), Julian C. Smith Jr.'s mother; cover is also inscribed "Mrs. Julian C. Smith"
      Montreal, Quebec
    - Julian C. Smith Sr. Obituaries, 1939-06-27-1958-11 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Includes copy of Shawinigan Journal
    - Bachelor of Arts Diploma from Good Counsel College for Joan Dolores Elsen, 1941-06-05; Good Counsel College (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Wife's undergraduate diploma
      Elsen, Joan Dolores; White Plains, New York
    - Assorted Family Records, 1944-12-1992-04-23 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Includes sketches, family photographs, Bertha Louise Alexander's will, Joslyn A. Smith obituaries, Smith family genealogy
    - Mother and Her Relatives: Recollections of Bertha Alexander Smith, 1994; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 1)
    - Family History: Julian C. Smith, Sr., 1997; Smith Jr., Julian C.; Brook, Diane L. (Box 1)
      Buffalo, New York; Montreal, Quebec
  - Photographs
    - Photos for Memoir, date unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Pocket-size Leather Photo Holder, undated (Box 8)
      Includes two photos, of Louise and Joslyn Smith on the right and most likely Bertha Smith on the right
    - Photo album, 1920-1940 (Box 8)
      Includes photos of Milan, Paris, United Kingdom
    - Photo album, 1920-1940 (Box 8)
      Front label: "Howard J + Julie / Beautiful western Black n White Photos / Ansel Adams"
    - Florence C. Smith Photo album, 1926-05-1932-05 (Box 8)
      Includes photos of Morocco, Tangier, Canada, Germany, France, Bermuda, Europe, loose photo of Julian's sister, Florence Smith and Stefanie Warden in 1985
    - Florence C. Smith Photo album, 1931-08-1940 (Box 8)
      Includes photos of French, Italy, Turkey, Syria, Lebanon, Israel, Egypt, Iraq, Jordan, New York, Japan
    - DuPont Photo Collage Poster, 1978-04 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Double-sided
    - Class of 1941 65th Reunion photo, 2006-06 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Includes note from Ed King '41 identifying everyone in the photo
  - Other
    - Hand Drawn Calendar, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Invitation/Announcement List, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Canadian Stamp History Photocopy, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chinese Painting, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Lyric Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Drawings in Pencil, 1934-10-20-1944-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes two sketchbooks
    - Collected Writings, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Newspapers, 1937-05-12-1945-08-15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes Canadian newspapers with headlines from King George VI's coronation, German and Japanese surrenders in World War II
    - Collected Writings, 1937-09-1984-06-01 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Assorted Writing, 1937-09-11-1983-01-04 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chart of Lake Memphremagog, 1938-10-12; Smith Sr., Julian Cleveland (Box 25, Folder 4)
      "This map with the data shown thereon was prepared during the years 1936, 1937, & 1938 by Julian Cleveland Smith. M.E., E.E., LL.D., Member E.I.C. Assisting in this work were J. Napolean Longval. C.E., and Alberta A. Heath Jr. A novel type supersonic sounding machine designed and built by Julian Cleveland Smith M.E., E.E., LL.D. and Arthur S. Runciman, E.E., Assoc. member E.I.C. was largely responsible for the successful completion of this work"
    - List of Places Lived In, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Victory Garden Plan, 1943-05 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Publicity, 1952-04-16-1994-02-11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Vitae & Lists of Publications, 1966-01-1994-01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Assorted Personal Materials, 1966-01-17-1989-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence, artciles 45th Reunion materials, sketches
    - Alumni Materials, 1976-1981-03-21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Includes list of Class of 1941 donors, correspondence
    - Canadian Stamp Related Materials, 1983-10-08-2004-12-04 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 50th Reunion Materials, 1991-06; MU-1728-1729; Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes Class of 1941 50th Reunion photo, buttons, programs, correspondence
    - Sheldrake Notes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Collected Writings, 2001-09-22-2012-10 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Canadian Stamp Auctions, 2004-01-24 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Drama Materials, 2011-2014-10-23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes Antimatter script and programs, River Gold score
    - There Once Was A Time, Long Ago…: My First 27 Years, 2014; Smith Jr., Julian Cleveland (Box 1)
  - Museum Items
    - Class of '41 baseball cap, undated; MU-1712; Cornell University (Box 24)
    - Savage Club Badges, undated; MU-1713-1714 (Box 24)
    - AIChE Fellow pin in box, undated; MU-1715 (Box 24)
    - Olin Hall of Chemical Engineering keychain, undated; MU-1716; Cornell University (Box 24)
    - Cornell University pin, undated; MU-1723; Cornell University (Box 24)
    - Cayuga Society paperweight, undated; MU-1724; Cornell University (Box 24)
    - Wooden Academic Baton, undated; MU-1725; Cornell University (Box 24)
    - Cornell University keychain, undated; MU-1719-1720; Cornell University (Box 24)
      2 copies
    - Sigma Xi Key Tie Tack, undated; MU-1721 (Box 24)
      engraved
    - Phi Kappa Phi pin & chain, 1941; MU-1722 (Box 24)
    - AIChE 50th Anniversary keychain, 1958; MU-1717 (Box 24)
    - Repaund Centennial keychain, 1980; MU-1718 (Box 24)
  - Reference Books
    - Microtexts in Cornell University Libraries: A Selective Guide, 1982; Smith, Joan E.; Cornell University Libraries (Box 3)
    - Microtexts in Cornell University Libraries: A Selective Guide. Supplement, 1986; Smith, Joan E.; Cornell University Libraries (Box 3)
      Includes library memo from June 1986
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1983, 1986; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1984, 1986; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1985, 1986; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1992, 1993; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal 10-Year Obituary Index 1980-1989, 1993; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1993, 1994; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1994, 1995; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal 15-Year Obituary Index 1860-1874, 1995; Smith Jr., Julian Cleveland (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1995, 1996; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal Obituary Index 1996, 1996; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal 15-Year Obituary Index 1900-1914, 1996; Smith Jr., Julian Cleveland (Box 23)
    - Ithaca Journal 10-Year Obituary Index 1990-1999, 2000; Smith, Joan E.; Smith Jr., Julian C. (Box 23)
    - A Guide to the Classical Collections of Cornell University, 2003; Kuniholm, Peter I.; Ramage, Nancy H,; Ramage, Andrew (Box 3)
    - Memorial Statements & Related Materials
      - Clyde Mason Memorial Statement, 1952-03-31-1984-02-09 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Charles C. Winding Memorial Statement, 1986-04-02-1986-05-20 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Memorial Statements: Cornell University Faculty 1868-1990, 1987-1991; Smith Jr., Julian Cleveland (Box 3)
        2nd Edition; includes two memos on Memorial Statements
      - Memorial Statements: Cornell University Faculty 2012-2013, 2012-07-01-2013-06-30; Cornell's Office of the Dean of Faculty (Box 3)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Personal Correspondence
    - US Citizenship Correspondence & Records, 1942-02-1960-06 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1947-01-03-1950-06-07 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1969-03-2004-09 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Primarily includes Who's Who in the World and Venezuela mission correspondence
    - David S. Lermond, 1982-12-09 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Cruise Europe's Caribbean, 1990-02 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Various Correspondence, 2002-06-2011-04 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cards, 2010-08-10 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Professional Correspondence
    - Military Correspondence, 1939-09-14-1945-12-11 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Includes letters concerning the Manhattan Project
    - Centrifuges - Popular Article, 1947-06-1948-05 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Acquaintances, 1948-07-1961 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      Includes Class of 1941 20th Reunion directory, business cards, notes
    - Soil Solidification Correspondence, 1950-05-31-1958-03-04 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Interchemical Corp. Correspondence, 1950-10-04-1951-02-15 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Chrome Lignin Process Publicity & Correspondence, 1951-01-05-1964-07-13 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - GLF Correspondence, 1951-06-09-1952-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Size Reduction, 1951-09-19-1958-01-23 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Chrome Lignin Process Inquiries & Correspondence, 1951-12-1961-04-07 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Equipment Book - Original Correspondence & Contract, 1952-01-03-1952-07-22 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Eastman Oil Well Survey Company, 1952-06-12-1957-04-08 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Contract papers, Correspondence with ERDL, 1952-07-15-1954-10-13 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Contract number: DA-44-009 eng 1156
    - Eng 1531 - Correspondence with Manufacturers, 1952-09-29-1954-04-07 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Eng 1531, 1953-02-27-1954-08-19 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Professional Engineering License Application, 1953-10-15-1958-05-13 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Includes correspondence, notes, Engineering and Land Surveying Handbook
    - American Institute of Chemists, 1957-03-27-1980-05-02 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Perry Handbook - Correspondence, 1959-03-24-1964-02-25 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1959-08-31-1976-04-08 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Perry Handbook 4th Edition - Permissions, 1959-10-05-1961-01-16 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Thomas L. Singman, 1960-07-29-1982-06-09 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Perry Handbook - Proof Correspondence, 1962-01-12-1963-05-21 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Beet Sugar Study - Correspondence, 1963-06-28-1964-06-03 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - University of Florida, 1963-08-1965-04 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1965-04-15-1965-07-25 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Cornell Correspondence, 1965-06-30-2015-01-06 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - References, 1965-10-28-1993-08-09 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Instant Anything" Stabilized Landing Pads, 1965-11-1965-12-20 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - A Correspondence, 1965-12-22-1972-07-31 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - S Correspondence, 1967-01-05-1975-11-12 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - F Correspondence, 1967-01-11-1972-08-30 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Ohio University, 1967-03-10-1969-02-12 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - B Correspondence, 1967-04-12-1974-08-05 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - C Correspondence, 1967-08-11-1975-08-04 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - G Correspondence, 1967-08-11-1973-07-25 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - M Correspondence, 1967-08-11-1975-07-25 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - U-V-W Correspondence, 1967-08-11-1975-08-04 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - K Correspondence, 1967-08-14-1971-10-21 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - X-Y-Z Correspondence, 1967-08-14-1967-10-27 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - H Correspondence, 1967-08-30-1972-10-10 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - D Correspondence, 1968-08-14-1971-09-08 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - P-Q Correspondence, 1968-08-14-1975-07-15 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Samuel C. Fleming, 1968-08-22-1970-08-11 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - L Corresopndence, 1968-09-06-1975-07-30 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - E Correspondence, 1969-08-06-1972-09-06 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - T Correspondence, 1969-08-18-1974-09-11 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Brazil, 1970-05-28-1970-08-27 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - I-J Correspondence, 1970-07-17-1970-09-01 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - NSF Travel Grant, 1970-09-15-1972-09-06 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence - Outside, 1971-09-29-1972-11-07 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence - University of Edinburgh, 1971-12-1973-02-16 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - N Correspondence, 1973-08-17-1975-10-08 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Elmer L. Gaden Jr., 1973-10-19 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Dr. Jose A. Fernandez Lozano, 1975-03-12-1982-11-29 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - N. Blakebrough, 1975-10-24-1978-03-16 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Dr. John Eckert - Norton Company, 1975-10-24-1976-11-08 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - D. O. Shah, 1975-11-30-1978-12-05 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Donald B. Gordon, 1976-02-10-1978-10-23 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Archives Records, 1976-05-03-1978-10-17 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hassan Elmayergi, 1976-06-11-1978-09-19 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - K.B. Bischoff, 1976-08-24-1979-02-28 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Charles R. Nelson, 1976-11-05-1976-11-15 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Arthur S. Wenborne File, 1977-01-05-1989-04-14 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      Incudes correspondence, articles
    - Kiyomi Akita, 1977-01-31 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Jozsef M. Berty, 1977-04-04-1977-11-18 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Robert D. Bradford, 1977-08-26-1977-09-13 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Constance E. Cook, 1977-09-06-1977-09-30 (Box 9, Folder 38)